毕尔包,西班牙
瑞士工业银行
庞德先生 谢谢你百忙之中
So good of you to come see me, Mr. Bond.
还能抽空赶来
Particularly on such short notice.
如果信不过瑞士银行家 这世界会变成什么样子？
lf you can't trust a Swiss banker, what's the world come to?
既然大家都准备好了
And now that we're all comfortable...
请坐好吗？
...why don't you sit down?
我费了点工夫
It was not easy...
终于拿回钱
...but I have retrieved the money.
罗伯爵士一定会很高兴的
No doubt Sir Robert will be pleased to see it again.
以目前的汇率来计算 扣掉手续费
At the current rate of exchange, minus the fees and certain...
和一些额外费用
...unforeseeable expenses.
这就是收据
Voila, the receipt.
你要过目吗？
Would you like to check my figures?
我确定数字是正确的
I'm sure they're perfectly rounded.
全都在这儿
It's all there.
我不是为钱来的
I didn't come for the money.
罗伯爵士买的报告
The report Sir Robert bought was stolen...
是从一个为它而死的 情报员手中偷来的
...from an Ml6 agent who was killed for it.
我要知道凶手是谁
I want to know who killed him.
-真惨 -我只要名字
-Terrible tragedy. -I just want a name.
我只是中间人 把钱归还原主
I am merely the middleman. I'm trying to do the honorable thing...
算是很有良心了
...returning the money to its rightful owner.
这对瑞士银行家来说 是多不简单的事啊
We know how difficult that can be for a Swiss banker.
我给你机会把钱带走
I am offering you the opportunity to walk out with the money.
我给你机会把命留下来
And I'm giving you the opportunity to walk out with your life.
照目前的情况看来
Looking at our present situation...
身为一个银行家,我得说你没有
...as a banker, I'd have to say...
说这种狠话的本钱
...that the numbers are not on your side.
也许你没有看到
Perhaps you failed to take into account...
我潜在的资本
...my hidden assets.
现在是我占上风
You've had a small reversal of fortune.
-把名字说出来 -办不到
-Give me the name. -I can't tell you.
咱们数到三
Let's count to three.
你一定办得到,对吗？
You can do that, can't you?
一
One.
二
Two.
好
All right.
不过你得保护我
But you'll have to protect me--
MI6情报总局 伦敦
詹姆斯
James.
你有没有带礼物送我？
Have you brought me a souvenir from your trip?
巧克力？
Chocolates?
订婚戒？
An engagement ring?
你一定喜欢这玩意
I thought you'd enjoy one of these.
真浪漫
How romantic.
我知道该放哪
I know exactly where to put that.
梦妮
Oh, Moneypenny.
就像我俩的关系
The story of our relationship:
食之无味,弃之可惜
Close, but no cigar.
抱歉打扰了,007 请你进来一下？
I hate to tear you away from affairs of state. Would you mind coming in?
马上来,M夫人
Right away, M.
罗伯金恩爵士 这是詹姆斯庞德
Sir Robert King, James Bond.
你帮我找回我的钱,谢谢 干得好
The man who retrieved my money. Thank you. Excellent work.
你要小心,M夫人 我可能会把他挖走的
Be careful, M. I might steal him from you.
建筑不是我的专长
Construction's not exactly my specialty.
事实上,他是专门搞破坏的
Quite the opposite, in fact.
帮我问候你家人
Best to the family.
老朋友吗？
Old friend?
我们在牛津一起念法律
We read law at Oxford together.
我早就知道他会称霸天下
I always knew he'd conquer the world.
要喝一杯吗？
Care for a drink?
好,谢谢
Yes, thank you.
他的为人很有原则
He's a man of great integrity.
却花三百万英镑 买失窃报告
Who buys stolen reports for 3 million pounds.
谢谢
Thank you.
有狙击手的线索吗？
Any leads on the sniper?
没有
Not one.
是职业高手做的
Professional job.
一定受人指使
She must be working for someone.
-这就是失窃报告？ -对
-Is this the stolen report? -Yes. Classified.
从苏俄原子能源部来的 机密文件
From the Russian Atomic Energy Department.
金恩要这个干什么？
What would King want this for?
他以为这项秘密报告
He was led to believe the document was a secret report...
指认了个一直在破坏 他新的输油管的恐怖份子
...identifying the terrorists who'd attacked his new oil pipeline.
有意思
Interesting.
但这没解释为什么有人救我
It doesn't explain why someone would want me out of their office alive.
金恩！那笔钱
King! The money.
梦妮,拦住金恩
Moneypenny, stop King.
让开！让开！
Move! Move, move!
快让开！
Get out of the way!
住手！
Stop!
让开！
Move!
快让开！
Get out of the way! Move!
住手！
Stop, stop!
那还没完成呢！
It isn't finished!
放开！
Let go!
-你在干--？ -放开！
-What do you think you're--? -Let go!
听我说！
Listen to me!
你逃不了的
You can't get away.
跟我合作 说出背后主使
We can make a deal. Tell me who's behind this...
你替谁工作？
...who you work for.
住手！
Don't do it!
别把我们炸死！
Don't blow us up!
我能保护你
I can protect you.
明白吗？ 谁也不能伤害你
Do you understand? I can protect you.
他就能！
Not from him!
纵横天下
亲爱的
Hello, my dear.
那女孩是谁？
Who is that young woman?
金恩的女儿
King's daughter.
伊莉翠
Elektra.
谢谢
Thank you.
钞票浸过尿素
The money was dipped in urea.
-MI6情报局总部苏格兰 -威力强大的肥料炸药
A highly compacted fertilizer bomb.
007的手碰过钞票 又摸到冰块
Having handled the money, the water on 007's hands...
于是引起化学反应
...when he touched the ice, started a chemical reaction.
有一张钞票的反伪造金属线 被换成镁制引信
In one note, the anti-counterfeiting strip was replaced with magnesium...
金恩的胸针
...which acted as a detonator. And King's lapel pin...
也被换成
...was switched for a copy...
引爆炸药的无线电发送器
...which contained a radio transmitter to trigger the blast.
换句话说 他引爆炸弹炸死自己的
In other words, he set off the bomb that killed him.
我们知道凶手是金恩的亲信
We know it was someone close to King...
唯一的线索却 在气球上自杀身亡
...and our only lead committed suicide on that balloon.
金恩企业规模如此庞大
But given the size of King's organization...
想找出凶手 简直就是海底捞针
...it could be anyone, anywhere.
绝不能饶过他们
This will not stand.
不能让一个懦夫 利用我们
We won't be terrorized by cowards who'd murder an innocent man...
残杀无辜
...and use us as the tool.
我们一定要找出凶手
We'll find those who committed this atrocity.
就算追到天涯海角
We'll follow them to the farthest ends of the earth, if needs be.
也要将他们绳之以法
And we will bring them to justice.
谭纳！
Tanner!
M夫人说你不能参与行动 除非得到医生批准
M says you're off the active-duty list until you're cleared by medical.
锁骨脱臼
Dislocated collarbone.
要是扯断韧带 你就得休养好几星期
If any more tendons snap, I'm afraid you'll be out of action for weeks.
茉莉
Molly...
我需要一张健康证明
...I need a clean bill of health.
你得给我出健康证明
You have to clear me for duty.
-那是很不… -道德？
-That wouldn't really be-- -Ethical?
实际
Practical.
真聪明
Smart.
咱们不能
Well, let's just...
拉点裙带关系吗？
...skirt the issue, shall we?
这次你一定要打电话给我
You'd have to promise to call me...
一定要
...this time.
大夫命令,不敢不从
Whatever the doctor orders.
只要你有持久的耐力
I suppose if you stayed in constant contact--
当然有
Of course.
如果你有足够的体力
If you showed sufficient stamina...
-不要做任何… -剧烈运动？
-...cut out all kinds of-- -Strenuous activity?
这种音乐真的很霹雳 对吧,Q先生？
I suppose we all have to pay the piper sometime, right, Q?
007,少罗唆
Oh, pipe down, 007.
我得罪你了吗？
Was it something I said?
没有 只是你毁了
No. Something you destroyed.
我的船
My fishing boat.
我打算退休以后
For my retirement...
离你远点
...away from you.
介绍你个小伙子
Now, I want to introduce you to the young fellow...
当我的接班人
...I'm grooming to follow me.
门打开会比较好
Helps to open the door.
你是？
And you might be...?
他是007
This is 007.
如果你是Q先生 他一定是R先生了？
If you're Q, does that make him R?
007情报员果然机智过人
Yes, the legendary 007 wit.
只是英雄无用武之地
Or at least half of it.
我敢保证你一定会
Now, I dare say, 007, that you've met...
对这辆车很满意
...your match with this machine.
全新车款？ 更健全的配备？
New model? Improved specs?
你不是受伤休养吗？
I thought you were on the inactive roster. Some injury?
等着瞧吧
We'll see about that.
这辆车有最先进的反制武器
As I was saying, the very latest in interception countermeasures.
钛合金车体 多功能显示荧幕
Titanium armor, a multitasking heads-up display...
六个饮料杯座
...and six beverage cup holders.
可以说是应有尽有
All in all, rather stocked.
应该是“配备齐全”
''Fully loaded,'' I think is the term.
-我想… -你在这不能想
-I think-- -You're not here to think.
你在这只能听我的
You're here to do what I tell you.
去把外套穿上
Now, go put on the coat...
为007示范一下
...and demonstrate it for 007.
好
But of course.
007,你要仔细看了
Now watch closely, please, 007.
右手伸入右袖
The right arm goes in the right sleeve, thus...
左手伸入左袖
...and the left arm in the left sleeve, thus.
仔细看,上面有口袋、拉链
Note closely, please: pockets, poppers and zipper.
把拉链的下方
Take the lower part of the zipper...
插入正确的位置…
...and insert it into--
你就扯吧
Pull the tag.
你不是说…
You said--
他已经整装待发了
He seems well-suited for the job.
你不会这么早退休
You're not retiring anytime soon...
对不对？
...are you?
007,仔细听好
Now, pay attention, 007.
我一直想教你两件事
I've always tried to teach you two things:
第一,别向敌人露出弱点
First, never let them see you bleed.
第二呢？
And the second?
一定要知道如何逃命
Always have an escape plan.
罗伯金恩爵士接手伊苏密
晚安,伊莉翠绑案已结束
Good evening. The Elektra King kidnap ordeal is over.
警方说她射杀两名匪徒
The Cyprus authorities say she has escaped...
成功逃出歹徒手中
...after shooting dead two of her captors and is--
他对我大叫
He shouted.
一直大吼大叫
Shouted all the time.
五百万美金
兑换三百万英镑
汇率
三百万英镑
兑换五百万美金
-禁止进入 -需要一级特准
Level one clearance required.
需要一级特准
有什么事,007？
Yes, 007?
跟我谈谈伊莉翠的绑案
Tell me about the kidnapping of Elektra King.
我不知道你参与此案
I wasn't aware you had an assignment on this case.
我带回来的那些钱杀了金恩
I brought the money in that killed King.
-不要觉得太内疚 -我没有,你呢？
-Don't make this personal. -I'm not. Are you?
只有你能封锁她的档案
You're the only one who could seal her file.
容我们失陪一下可以吗？
Will you excuse us?
我不能容许你抗命行事
I will not tolerate insubordination, 007.
发生什么事？
What happened?
伊莉翠遭到绑架后
After Elektra King was kidnapped...
他父亲想私下解决
...her father tried to deal with it on his own...
但徒劳无功
...with no success.
于是他来找我
So he came to me.
你知道我们不向 恐怖份子妥协
As you are aware, we do not negotiate with terrorists.
于是我不顾我的直觉
And against every instinct in my heart...
还有我的母性
...every emotion as a mother...
我叫他不要付赎金
...I told him not to pay the ransom.
我以为时间很充裕
I thought we had time on our side.
你把她当诱饵
You used the girl as bait.
那笔钱的金额
The money in King's briefcase was the same amount...
跟莉莉翠的赎金等值
...as the ransom demand for his daughter.
这是个警告
It's a message.
那个恐怖份子又出现了
Your terrorist is back.
维特苏卡斯
Victor Zokas.
别号是
A.k.a....
雷纳
Renard.
无政府主义份子
The anarchist.
1996年他在莫斯科行动 之前在北韩平壤活动
He was operating in Moscow in 1 996. Pyongyang, North Korea before that.
他也曾出没在…
And he's been spotted...
阿富汗、伊拉克、伊朗 贝鲁特、高棉
...in Afghanistan, Bosnia, Iraq, Iran, Beirut and Cambodia.
全都是浪漫的渡假胜地
All the romantic vacation spots.
他唯一的目的是天下大乱
His only goal is chaos.
罗伯来找我后 我派009去刺杀雷纳
After Robert came to me, I sent 009 to kill Renard.
但计划还没完成
Before he completed the mission...
伊莉翠先逃出来
...Elektra escaped.
一星期后 我们的人找到雷纳
A week later, our man caught up with him.
向他脑袋开一枪
He put a bullet in his head.
子弹至今还留在里面
That bullet's still there.
他怎么能活下来？
How did he survive?
救了他的医生无法取出子弹
The doctor who saved Renard couldn't get the bullet out...
雷纳就杀了他
...so Renard killed him.
子弹入脑髓 阻断他所有的感觉
It's moving through the medulla oblongata, killing off his senses.
包括触觉,嗅觉
Touch, smell.
他也感觉不到痛楚
He feels no pain.
他的体力和耐力比常人强
He can push himself harder, longer than any normal man.
子弹还是会致命的
The bullet will kill him...
但在死前 他会越来越强壮
...but he'll grow stronger every day until the day he dies.
罗伯死了
Robert is dead.
MI6丢了面子
Ml6 is humiliated.
他已经报了大仇
He's had his revenge.
还没有
Not quite.
雷纳有三个仇人
Renard had three enemies in that kidnapping.
还剩下一个
And there's still one he hasn't touched.
伊莉翠
Elektra.
医生批准你出任务
I see the good doctor has cleared you.
说你有过人的体力
Notes you have exceptional stamina.
她一定是对这一点
I'm sure she was touched by his dedication...
有亲身的体验
...to the job in hand.
我要你去保护伊莉翠
007, I want you to go to Elektra.
她继承父业 在架设输油管
She's taken over the construction of her father's oil pipeline.
找出更换胸针的内贼
Find who switched that pin.
如果你的直觉是对的 雷纳会回来
If your instincts are right, Renard will be back...
下个目标就是伊莉翠
...and Elektra will be the next target.
她又要当诱饵了
The worm on the hook again.
她不需要知道 同一个人想杀她
She doesn't need to know the same man may be after her.
别把她吓坏
Don't frighten her.
这算是卧底行动？
A shadow operation?
记住
Remember...
只能卧底查案
...shadows stay in front or behind.
不能卧到她床上去
Never on top.
亚塞拜然
你得回去 这地方被封锁了
You, go back. Leave. This area is closed.
我来见伊莉翠金恩
I'm here to see Elektra King.
詹姆斯庞德 环球贸易公司
James Bond, Universal Exports.
我是安全主任大卫朵夫
And I'm Davidov, chief of security.
你可以看到村民 正在示威抗议
We're having problems with the villagers.
我请金小姐留在巴库的公司
I've told Miss King to stay at the office in Baku.
可恶
Oh, hell.
-金小姐,我请你别来的 -我知道
-Miss King, I told you to-- -I know what you told me.
把油管得绕过这儿
Send the pipe around.
这会多花时间和多花几百万元
It's going to take weeks and cost millions.
-令尊同意这条路线 -他错了,去做吧
-Your father approved this route. -Then my father was wrong. Do it.
-大卫朵夫 -我去跟她说
-Davidov-- -I'll talk to her.
我在先父的葬礼上见过你
I saw you at my father's funeral.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
M夫人说要派人来 你是？
M told me she was sending someone. Mr...?
庞德
Bond.
詹姆斯庞德
James Bond.
你认识先父吗？
Did you know my father?
只有一面之缘
I met him once, briefly.
你遗传了他的外交手腕
You seem to have inherited his touch for diplomacy.
你是说保住教堂？
Saving the church?
也避免流血事件
And avoiding the bloodshed.
一百年前,先母的娘家 发现这儿的石油
1 00 years ago, my mother's family discovered the oil here.
当时苏联刚立国
When the Soviet Union was formed...
共产党在接下来的70年内
...the Communists spent the next 70 years...
在此大肆破坏
...plundering our countryside for it.
我在来的路上看到 他们造成的破坏
I saw their mess on the drive in.
新的输油管能让我们致富
The new pipeline will guarantee our future.
但不能毁掉我们宝贵的历史
But it would be a crime to destroy what little is left of our past.
你不是来此谈石油的 对吧？
But you didn't come here to talk about oil, did you?
告诉我
Tell me...
你曾失去过亲人吗？
...have you ever lost a loved one, Mr. Bond?
M夫人让我来因为 你有生命危险
M sent me because your life might be in danger.
来,我给你看样东西
Please, I want to show you something.
这条输油管长达八百英哩 经过土耳其
I'm trying to build an 800-mile pipeline through Turkey...
有恐怖份子的伊拉克
...past the terrorists in Iraq...
伊朗和叙利亚
...Iran and Syria.
上面这儿
Up here...
苏俄也有三条输油管
...the Russians have three competing pipelines...
他们会不择手段阻止我
...and they'll do anything to stop me.
先父被杀 村民暴动
My father was murdered, the villagers are rioting...
你大老远来
...and you have come all this way...
就告诉我说我可能会有危险
...to tell me that I ''might'' be in danger?
我们怀疑有内贼
We suspect there is an insider.
这是先父的胸针
My father's pin.
不,这是复制品
No, a duplicate.
内藏的发送器 引爆炸药
With a transmitter inside that set off the bomb.
先父曾向情报局求助两次
My family has relied on Ml6 twice, Mr. Bond.
我不会犯同样的错
I won't make that mistake a third time.
输油管一定会完成
I'm going to finish building this pipeline...
我不需要你的帮忙
...and I don't need your help.
失陪了 我得去检查测量管线
If you'll excuse me, I have to check the survey lines.
我也很想检查测量管线
I've always wanted to check the survey lines.
你不肯轻易放弃,不是吗？
You don't take no for an answer.
你最好会滑雪
I hope you know how to ski, then.
我早知道你会冷若冰霜
I came prepared for a cold reception.
风太强
Can't land.
无法降落
Wind's too strong.
稳住直升机
Hold her steady.
你滑得很好
You ski very well, Mr. Bond.
你好像很爱被人追
Seems you enjoy being chased.
大概经常发生吧
Happens all the time.
没你想的这么经常
Less often than you might think.
那两条输油管
So this is where they meet...
就是在这儿交接的
...the two ends of the pipeline.
这是令尊的遗志
Your father's legacy.
这是我的家族
My family's legacy...
对世界的贡献
...to the world.
-在等人吗？ -没有
-Expecting visitors? -No.
这些人来者不善
This isn't a social call.
你到谷底 我引他们到树林
Head for the gully. I'll lead them into the trees.
快去！
Go, go!
山脚下见
See you back at the lodge.
-没事 -我们被活埋！
-It's all right. -We're buried alive!
我不能留在这！
I can't stay here!
你不会
You're not going to.
我不能呼吸！
I can't breathe! I can't breathe!
看着我,伊莉翠,看着我！ 看着我的眼睛
Look at me. Elektra, look at me! Look at my eyes.
看着我的眼睛
Look at my eyes.
看我的眼睛！
Look at my eyes!
你没有事
You're all right.
一切都没事了
Everything's all right.
相信我
Trust me.
巴库
她很好
She's fine.
只有一些瘀青 并无大碍
Some bumps and bruises, but otherwise fine.
她想见你 不是你,是他
She wants to see you. Not you, Davidov. Him.
你还好吧？
Are you all right?
我得问你一件事
I need to ask you something.
我要你说实话
And I want you to tell me the truth.
是谁？
Who is it?
到底是谁想杀我？
Who's trying to kill me?
我说过,我不知道
I told you, I don't know.
不过我会找到他
But I'm gonna find him.
这不够好
Not good enough.
绑案后我很害怕
After the kidnapping, I was afraid.
我不敢出门 不敢独处
I was afraid to go outside. I was afraid to be alone.
不敢靠近人群
I was afraid to be in a crowd.
我什么都不敢做
I was afraid to do anything at all.
直到我惊觉
Until I realized...
我不能躲在阴影下
...I can't hide in the shadows.
我不能一辈子都害怕
I can't let fear run my life.
绝对不能
I won't.
我找到他以后
After I find him...
你就不需要再害怕
...you won't have to.
别走
Don't go.
留下来陪我
Stay with me.
求求你？
Please?
不行
I can't do that.
我以为你的职责是要 保护我的安全
I thought it was your job to protect me.
你在这儿很安全
You'll be safe here.
我不想要安全
I don't want to be safe.
我很快就会回来
I'll be back soon.
现在到底谁在害怕 庞德先生？
And who's afraid now, Mr. Bond?
我要见魏伦汀苏考斯基
I want to see Valentin Zukovsky.
不可能
Impossible.
伏特加马丁尼
Vodka martini.
用摇的,别用搅的
Shaken, not stirred.
就说詹姆斯庞德找他
Tell him James Bond is here.
快去
Now.
我看你是没听清楚
I don't think you heard me.
苏先生很乐意见你
Mr. Zukovsky would be delighted to see you.
你先请
After you.
不,你先请
我坚持
I insist.
你也来一点
And a little for you.
庞德！詹姆斯庞德！
Bond! James Bond!
这是妮娜
Meet Nina.
和薇洛丝卡
And Verushka.
叫她们走
Lose the girls, Valentin.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
我为什么突然觉得 我买的保险还不够？
Why am I suddenly worried that I'm not carrying enough insurance?
别紧张,老詹
Chill out, James.
好吧,各位
Fine, ladies.
快滚！
Go on. Beat it. Scram.
蛮牛,把钱给她们
Bull, give them an inch.
要确定她们在我赌场都输光
And make sure they lose it in this casino.
后会有期,庞德先生
I'll see you later, Mr. Bond.
你的钱都存在你的嘴巴里
I see you put your money where your mouth is.
蛮牛信不过银行
Mr. Bullion does not trust banks.
你想聊什么？
So what would you like to talk about?
我恐怕帮不上忙
I'm not sure I can really help you.
我现在都做合法生意
I'm a legitimate businessman now.
来点我的苏氏极品鱼子酱？
Would you care for some caviar? My own brand: Zukovsky's Finest.
你看看
Look at this.
苏俄特种部队
Russian Special Services.
原子能源部的反恐怖份子单位
Atomic Energy Antiterrorist Unit.
哪儿找到的？
Where did you find this?
我从一个今早想刺杀 伊莉翠金恩的人的身上拿到的
I took it off a Parahawk which tried to kill Elektra King this morning.
幕后主使是雷纳
Renard is behind this.
咱们最好先喝一杯
I think you and I had better have a drink.
阿富汗事件后 KGB认为
And then after Afghanistan, the KGB decided...
雷纳太危险 于是把他开除
...Renard was a liability and just cut him loose.
他现在独立作业
Now he works freelance.
他替谁工作？
But for whom?
四条输油管互相竞争
There are four competing pipelines.
我打赌这里有一半的赌客
I'm willing to bet half the customers in this casino would be...
都想金恩输油管消失
...very happy to see the King pipeline disappear.
-有什么好笑？ -没什么,只是
-What's funny? -Nothing. It appears...
金小姐很大胆
...Miss King does not share your concern.
你来这儿干嘛？
What are you doing here?
跟你一样
The same thing you are.
找出想杀我的歹徒
Looking for the people who tried to kill me.
让我现在就带你回家
Let me take you home. Now.
不,我要证明我不怕
No. I want them to see I'm not frightened.
金小姐,很高兴见到你
Miss King, how very nice to see you.
我免费为你保留了令尊的位子
We've kept your father's chair free.
免费？ 拜托,这里什么都要钱
Free? Nothing comes free from you.
令尊有一百万美元的信用
Your father had a credit line with us. One million U.S.
你也一样有这个特权
I'd be happy to extend you that courtesy.
你想玩点什么？
So what's it to be?
21点,令尊的最爱？
Blackjack, your father's favorite?
咱们干脆一点
Let's keep it simple.
一翻两瞪眼
One card.
赌大一点
High draw.
一百万元
A million dollars.
等等
Wait.
前三张抽掉
Bury the top three cards.
你下定决心想保护我
You're determined to protect me.
你太任性了 别这么做
From yourself. You don't have to do this.
如果不能随心所欲 活着也没有意义
There's no point in living if you can't feel alive.
红心皇后
Queen of hearts.
你碰上了克星
It appears you've been beaten...
黑桃A
...by the ace of clubs.
别难过,亲爱的
No hard feelings, my dear.
下次再来
Come again soon.
走了吗？
Shall we?
我玩不起这种游戏
This is a game I can't afford to play.
我知道
I know.
-大卫朵夫呢？ -我放他一晚的假
-What happened to Davidov? -I gave him the night off.
欢迎光临魔鬼窟
Welcome to the Devil's Breath.
数千年来印度朝圣者 前来此地
For thousands of years, Hindu pilgrims journeyed to this holy place...
见识永不熄灭的神迹之火
...to witness the wonder of the natural flames that never die...
他们为了证明
...and to test their devotion...
对神的信仰
...to God...
一边握住滚烫的石块
...by holding the scalding rocks in their hands...
一边向神祷告
...as they said their prayers.
大卫朵夫,告诉我
Tell me, Davidov...
今天下午出了什么事？
...what happened this afternoon?
你保证过给我最顶尖的手下
You promised me your best men.
艾考夫提供最新的武器
Mr. Arkov supplied the latest weapons.
没错,可是庞德…
Yes, but Bond--
庞德手无寸铁
Bond was unarmed.
你呢,艾考夫？ 都准备好了吗？
And you, Arkov? Is everything ready for tomorrow?
授权书和通行证在车上
I have the authorization and passes in the car.
飞机今晚就到 不过…
I have arranged for a plane tonight, but....
不过什么？
But what?
我们应该取消其它的任务
We should scrub the rest of the mission.
攻击直升机应该回去
The Parahawks were meant to be returned.
别人会对我起疑心
People will ask questions, even of me.
都是因为他的无能
All because of his incompetence.
我明白了
I see.
你说得对 应该惩罚他
I see you're right. He should be punished.
大卫朵夫,拿着
Davidov, hold this for me.
我太高估你了
It was wrong of me to expect so much of you.
杀了他
Kill him.
他不够忠心
He failed his test of devotion.
你可以坐他的位子
You can take his place.
你可以取代他
Take his I.D.
但一定要准时
And do be on time.
你的肩膀受伤了
Poor shoulder.
一定很痛
It looks painful.
得多照顾点
It needs constant attention.
我知道
I knew....
我第一次见到你
I knew when I first saw you.
我就知道事情会这样
I knew it would be like this.
这些冰块够了
Enough ice for one day.
你怎么活下来？
How did you survive?
我色诱守卫
I seduced the guards.
用我的身体
Used my body.
把他制伏
It gave me control.
然后拿了枪就扫射
And the rest, I got a gun and started shooting.
你呢？
And what about you?
你是怎么活下来的？
What do you do to survive?
我在美女身上
I take pleasure...
寻找乐趣
...in great beauty.
走吧,时候不早了
Let's go. It's getting late.
大卫朵夫呢？
What happened to Davidov?
他不是要来吗？
I was told to expect him.
他被埋在工作堆中
He was buried with work.
走吧,把你的东西带着
Let's go. Get your stuff.
咱们出发吧
Okay, come on.
走吧
Let's get out of here.
你迟到了
You're late.
带来了吗？
Did you bring it?
礼物呢？
The grease.
当然
Of course.
太好了
Excellent.
准备好,十分钟后开始
Get ready. We're 1 0 minutes out.
记得戴上通行证
But make sure you wear the I.D.
哈萨克 中亚
我出去透透气
I'm gonna go get some air.
欢迎,艾考夫博士 我很景仰您的研究
Welcome to Kazakhstan, Dr. Arkov. I'm a great admirer of your research.
这儿很少见到您这种大人物
It's not often we see someone of your stature here.
这是我的职责
I go where the work takes me.
你的运输证明呢？
By the way, you have the transport documents?
我从核弹里取出钸元素
I pulled the plutonium out of the one inside.
可以引爆了
You can detonate the triggers now.
她是拆除核弹专家
Look, our IDA physicist.
省点力气 她对男人没兴趣
Don't bother. Not interested in men.
相信我
Take my word for it.
今年出四次任务 她都没闹绯闻
This year we decommissioned four test sites. Not even a glimmer.
你来这儿有事？
Are you here for a reason?
还是想闹绯闻？
Or are you just hoping for a glimmer?
你是哪位？
And you are...?
米盖艾考夫 苏俄原子能源部
Mikhail Arkov. Russian Atomic Energy Department.
小姐是…？
Miss...?
琼斯博士
Doctor...
克莉莫丝琼斯
...Jones. Christmas Jones.
别拿我的名字开玩笑
And don't make any jokes. I've heard them all.
我不知道任何 关于博士的玩笑
I don't know any doctor jokes.
没问题 搭电梯下去
This is okay. Take the elevator down the hole.
你朋友已经在下面了
Your friends are already down there.
不必穿防护衣吗？
Don't I get some protection?
不必,艾考夫博士
No, Dr. Arkov.
下面的钸元素很安全
Down there it's weapons-grade plutonium. Reasonably safe.
上面有你们的俄制氢弹 漏出的氢元素
Up here we have leaking hydrogen bombs that your lab built...
这半年来我一直都在处理
...which I've spent the last six months cleaning up.
你要怕的应该是我
So if you need any protection at all, it's from me.
你的同事在等你
Your friends are waiting for you.
博士
Doctor.
你忘了吗？
Aren't you forgetting?
离开时请归还辐射标签
没错,谢谢你
Of course. Thank you.
对了
By the way....
以苏俄人来说 你的英文说得不错
我读过牛津大学
你在等大卫朵夫吗？
Expecting Davidov?
他吃了子弹,来不成
He caught a bullet instead of the plane.
下来
Get off.
给我闭嘴
Keep your mouth shut.
我早就死了 你杀不了我
You can't kill me. I'm already dead.
我看你还没死透
Not dead enough for me.
你应该感谢我
Show a little gratitude.
我在银行家的办公室救了你一命
I did spare your life at the banker's office.
没错
That's right.
我不能让你死 你那时候在替我工作
I couldn't kill you. You were working for me.
你把钱带回去 炸死金恩
You delivered the money, killed King.
现在你又把飞机带来
Now you brought me the plane.
你偷走核弹有什么计划？
What's your plan for the bomb?
你先说 还是你根本就没计划？
You first. Or could it be you don't have a plan?
核弹得留下来
That bomb will never leave this room.
你也一样
Neither will you.
被一个搞不清楚状况的人威胁
How sad to be threatened by a man...
真可悲
...who can't grasp what he's involved in.
什么都不信的人只会报仇
Revenge is not hard to fathom for a man who believes in nothing.
你相信什么？
And what do you believe in?
贪婪的资本主义？
Preservation of capital?
尽管开枪吧
Go ahead, shoot me.
我才不怕
I welcome it.
我的手下听见之后会杀了你
My men will hear the shot and kill you.
然后军队会赶来
And the firefight will bring down half the army from above.
我在二十分钟内没打电话
But when a certain phone call isn't made in 20 minutes...
伊莉翠就没命
...Elektra dies.
你在唬人
You're bluffing.
她很美,对吧？
She's beautiful, isn't she?
可惜你不是她的
You should have had her before...
第一个男人
...when she was innocent.
我替你开了她的苞
How does it feel...
的感觉怎样？
...to know I broke her in for you?
我通常不杀手无寸铁的人
I usually hate killing an unarmed man.
冷血杀手不好当
Cold-blooded murder is a filthy business.
我也厌倦了被处决
A man tires of being executed.
不过我对你没感觉
But in your case, I feel nothing...
就跟你一样
...just like you.
如果不能随心所欲 活着也没有意义
But then again, there's no point living if you can't feel alive.
-把枪放下！ -上校,走开！
-Drop the gun! -Keep away, colonel.
他是冒牌货 艾考夫博士已经63岁
He's an impostor. Dr. Arkov is 63 years old.
他和飞机上的人
This is your impostor.
才是冒牌货
Along with the men outside on the plane.
他们想要偷走核弹
They'll steal the bomb.
我叫你把枪放下！
I said drop it!
跪下来！
On your knees!
干得好
Well done.
他一定会杀死我们
He would've killed us all.
你跟他讲过话？
Did you speak to him?
对,他不是核能科学家
Yeah, but he's no atomic scientist.
我想是你允许他下来的
I suppose you were the one who allowed him down.
你逮到我
You had me...
不过我早知道你
...but I knew you couldn't...
肩负不了重任
...shoulder the responsibility.
我们继续吧
Without any interruptions, let's proceed.
生面孔太多 包括你的在内
Too many new faces are here, including yours.
在我满意之前,核弹就留在这
The bomb doesn't move until I am satisfied.
全都给我上去
All of you, to the surface, now.
快点,快走！
Come on! Go!
快走！
Move!
我们被封住了
They're sealing us in.
你是什么人？
Who are you?
我替英国政府工作
I work for the British government.
保持冷静
Stay calm.
别生气,庞德
No hard feelings, Mr. Bond...
咱们扯平了
...but we're even.
很快
Soon...
你就会没有感觉的
...you'll feel nothing at all.
把门封住！快！
Seal the door! Close it!
快！
Come on!
继续跑,快！
Keep going! Move! Hang on!
你这英国的间谍叫什么？
You're a British spy. Do you have a name?
庞德
The name's Bond.
詹姆斯庞德
James Bond.
别停下来！快跳！
Don't stop! Go, go! Jump!
他们跑不远
They won't get very far.
核子弹头都有定位晶片
Every warhead has a locator card.
我们可以追踪讯号
We can track the signal.
你是说这个吗？
You mean one of these?
雷纳的飞机在哪儿？
Do we have the range of Renard's plane?
可能在苏俄
Anywhere in this circle: Russia...
亚美尼亚,伊朗 哈萨克…
...Armenia, Iran, Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan--
抱歉打搅了 伊莉翠从巴库打来
Sorry to interrupt. Elektra is calling from Baku.
她用影像电话
It's on the video line.
放到大荧幕上
Put her on the wall screen.
对不起 我不想烦你
I'm sorry. I would never call you except...
不过詹姆斯失踪了
...James has disappeared.
他在半夜离开我的别墅
He left my villa in the middle of the night...
我的安全主任
...and my head of security has been found...
在机场附近遇害
...near a local airstrip, murdered.
我派人过去
I'll send someone out.
M夫人,你能来吗？
M, could you come?
我很担心
I can't help thinking...
下一个就是我
...I'm next.
马上送我过去
Get me out there.
快送我过去
Just get me out there.
贾柏？
Gabor?
你很惊？
Surprised?
怎么了？ 你疯了吗？
What's wrong with you? Are you crazy?
也许吧
Maybe.
也许我该问你
Maybe I should ask you.
毕竟
After all...
如果不能随心所欲 活着也没有意义
...''There's no point in living if you can't feel alive.''
这不是你的座右铭吗？
Isn't that right, Elektra? Isn't that your motto?
你在讲什么？
What do you mean?
还是你老友雷纳教你的？
Or did you steal it from your old friend Renard?
我跟他聊了一下 他连我的肩伤在哪都知道
He and I had a chat. Knew all about us. Knew about my shoulder.
知道怎么弄痛我
Knew exactly where to hurt me.
你是说雷纳想杀我？
Renard's the man who's trying to kill me?
少装了
Drop the act.
别再演戏了
It's over.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
你清楚得很
Oh, I think you do.
这叫做“斯德哥尔摩症候群”
It's called Stockholm syndrome.
绑架受害人的通病
Common in kidnappings.
受害人通常年轻天真
Young, impressionable victim.
平日受到百般呵护
Sheltered.
没有性经验
Sexually inexperienced.
手段高明的绑匪
A powerful kidnapper skilled in torture, manipulation.
受害人突然念头一闪
Something snaps in the victim's mind.
受害人爱上绑匪
The captive falls in love with her captor.
胡说八道
How dare you?
简直胡说八道
那个禽兽都不如的东西？
That animal. That monster?
他令我作呕
He disgusts me.
你也一样
You disgust me.
他知道你的肩伤,是吗？
So he knew where to hurt you, is that it?
你在丧礼上带着吊腕带
You had a sling on your arm at the funeral.
我不需要跟你上床也知道
And I didn't have to sleep with you to find that out.
他也这么说
He used your exact words.
你早就知道
So you knew.
你也知道他一直想杀我
You knew all the time he was out there, coming for me...
你却欺骗我
...and you lied.
你利用我
You used me.
你利用我当诱饵
You used me as bait.
你还和我做爱
And you made love to me.
为什么？
What?
你是在等他下次行动之前 打发时间吗？
To pass the time as you waited for him to strike?
他在输油管附近杀了十个人
He's struck again. Ten men are dead at the pipeline.
我跟你去
I'm coming with you.
随你便 我已打给M夫人了
You do what you want to do, but I've called M.
她会来指挥大局的
She's coming to take charge.
目前情况如何？
I want an update. Where do we stand?
雷纳的手下 把定位晶片抽掉
One of Renard's men took the locator card from the bomb...
无法追踪,可是…
...so we can't track it. But....
可是什么？
But what?
恕我直言
With all due respect...
你不应该来的
...I don't think you should be here.
我能提醒你我是因为你才来的
May I remind you that you're the reason I'm here, 007.
你违反命令 把她丢下
You disobeyed an order and left that girl alone.
也许她没有你想像的那么无辜
Perhaps that girl isn't as innocent as you think.
-你说什么？ -假如偷换
-What are you saying? -Suppose the inside man...
金恩胸针的内贼
...the one who switched King's lapel pin...
是个女内贼？
...turned out to be an inside woman?
她杀死父亲,破坏自家的油管？
She kills her father and attacks her own pipeline?
-为什么？图的是什么？ -我还不知道
-Why? To what end? -I don't know...yet.
你看
Look at that.
这里不太对
That's not right.
那是什么？
What is it?
侦查车
An observation rig.
在输油管内寻找裂缝
Travels in the pipe looking for cracks.
关掉
Shut it down.
没办法
I don't understand.
没有反应
It won't respond.
那地方没有炸弹,没有核弹的--
The place is clean. No sign of--
-核弹在输油管里 -我的天啊！
-The bomb is in the pipeline. -Oh, my God!
他们带核弹经过这里 这解释了之前的攻击
They brought it through here. That'd explain the attack.
炸弹被送往主控室
Heading for the oil terminal.
造成最大的破坏
Where it would do the most damage.
叫你的员工立刻疏散
Have your men evacuate that terminal.
你相信我了吧？
So now do you believe me?
这是紧急状况
This is an emergency situation. So please...
请立刻疏散
...clear the room. Do it.
他想要破坏输油管
He's going for the oil.
这是西方未来唯一的输油管
The one pipeline the West is counting on to supply our reserves.
你有办法吗？
Do you have an idea?
也许吧
Maybe.
炸弹有多远？ 速度有多快？
How far is the rig from the terminal? How fast is it traveling?
它在106哩外 时速70哩
It's 1 06 miles from the terminal, going 70 miles an hour.
有78分钟 还有侦查车吗？
We have 78 minutes. Is there another rig?
在炸弹前面有一辆
There's one parked in the passageway ahead of it.
-你能带我去吗？ -当然
-Charles, can you get me out there? -Of course.
慢着,你要去做的 是我想你要去做的吗？
Wait. Are you gonna do what I think you're gonna do?
-拆除核弹需要什么？ -我
-What do I need to defuse a bomb? -Me.
在这儿
There it is.
闸门在那儿
Hatch to the passageway.
你来操控 试着让炸弹赶上我们
You keep the speed up so the other rig catches up with us.
-我会等你的消息 -好
-I'll wait to hear from you. -Gotcha.
你会开这玩意吗？
You know how to drive this thing?
开这玩意不需要博士学位
Doesn't exactly take a degree in nuclear physics.
他们进了输油管
They're in the pipeline.
他们出发了
They're on the move.
快一点！
Faster!
只要有丝毫的机会 庞德就会成功
If there's the slightest chance, Bond will succeed.
他是最顶尖的情报员
He's the best we have...
不过我都没告诉过他
...though I'd never tell him.
希望你说得对
I hope you're right.
它来了！
Here it comes!
赶上来了,快一点！
It's closing up. Faster!
坐稳了！
Sit tight.
停不下来！刹车卡住了！
No brakes! The controls are jammed!
这是战略性弹头
It's a tactical fission device.
威力不大,稳住了
Low yield. Hold me steady.
你拆过几百个,对吧？
You've defused hundreds of these, right?
对,但不在这种情况下
Yeah, but they're usually standing still.
生命充满了挑战
Life's full of small challenges.
你看
Have a look at this.
螺丝头不见了
Someone stripped the screw heads.
有人动过这枚核弹
Someone's tampered with the bomb.
一半的钸元素不见了
Look, half the plutonium's missing.
你的意思是什么？ 它不能引起核爆吗？
So what are you saying? It couldn't go nuclear?
如果被引爆还是能炸死我们
There's still enough explosive to kill us both if the trigger goes off.
-让它爆炸 -我可以拆除
-Let it blow. -But I can stop it.
让它爆炸！
Let it blow!
相信我,别管它
Trust me. Leave it.
过去,过去！
Move down. Move down!
快跳！跳！
Jump! Go on, jump!
快！
Jump!
罗宾森报告说
Robinson's reporting.
这不是核弹
The bomb was a dud.
不过引爆还是能毁坏 一段50英尺长的油管
But the triggering charge blew out a 50-yard section of the pipe.
庞德呢？
And Bond?
没消息
Nothing.
很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
不过我有礼物要送你
But I have a gift for you.
先父的遗物
Something that belonged to my father.
他会希望你收下
He would've wanted you to have it.
现在不是时候
Perhaps this isn't the time.
求求你
Please.
他经常提到
He often spoke of how compassionately...
我被绑架时 你给他最真诚的建议
...you advised him on the best course of action during my kidnapping.
这是非常宝贵的
It's very valuable, you know.
我不想把胸针也炸掉
I couldn't let it explode with the rest of him.
很可惜那笔钱 没把你也给炸死
I was very upset when the money didn't kill both of you.
我以为没有机会了
I didn't think I'd get another chance.
后来你却自己把机会送上门
Then you dropped the answer right in my lap.
庞德
Bond.
你也说他是最顶尖的
And as you say, he's the best you have.
那是过去式了
Or should I say, ''had''?
把她带上直升机
Take her to the helicopter.
把手给我
Come on, give me your hand.
跳,跳！
Jump, jump!
你为什么这么做？
Do you wanna explain why you did that?
我能拆除的 你差点害死我们
I could've stopped it. You almost killed us.
我们是死了
I did kill us.
她以为我们死了 她的诡计就得逞
She thinks we're dead, and she thinks she got away with it.
我不是间谍 请你白话一点
Do you wanna put that in English for those of us who don't speak ''spy''?
你在说谁？
Who's ''she''?
伊莉翠金恩
Elektra King.
她干嘛要炸掉自己的输油管？
Why would she blow up her own pipeline?
为了证明她的无辜
It makes her look innocent.
爆炸掩饰钸元素遭窃的事实
The explosion covers up the theft of the plutonium.
使人误为恐怖份子攻击
It looks like a terrorist attack.
但为什么留下这一半钸元素？
But why leave this half?
留下这些钸元素 才能掩饰他们偷走的另一半
So there's enough to spread around to cover up what they did take.
他们拿另一半干嘛？
What will they do with the other half?
这分量做不出核弹
It's not enough to make a nuclear bomb.
-你是专家,你解释给我听 -我不知道
-You're the scientist, you tell me. -I don't know.
天下最凶狠的恐怖份子 偷走六公斤的钸元素
But the world's greatest terrorist running around with 6 kilos...
不会干好事
...of plutonium can't be good.
我不拿回来 就会被打屁股
I have to get it back, or somebody will have my ass.
那个以后再说
First things first.
呼叫罗宾逊,收到吗？
Bond to Robinson. Do you copy?
对了 跟你合作之前
By the way, before we go any further...
我想先知道
...I just wanna know....
你跟伊莉翠有什么关系？
What's the story with you and Elektra?
现在只有敌对关系
We're strictly platonic. Now.
罗宾逊,收到吗？
Bond to Robinson. Copy?
你呢？
What's your story?
你怎么会跑到哈萨克？
What are you doing here in Kazakhstan?
跟你一样 逃避这些问题
Avoiding those kind of questions, just like you.
我收到了,紧急状况
I read you, 007. Red alert.
M夫人跟伊莉翠一起失踪了 还有三人挂彩
M is missing with Elektra. Three men down.
等待指示
Await instructions. Out.
我们该怎么办？
What do we do now?
我忘了一件很关键的事
I may have overlooked one critical element.
是什么？更多钸元素吗？
What? More plutonium?
不是
Beluga.
俄制鱼子酱
Caviar.
伊斯坦堡,土耳其
你带什么给我？
Brought me something?
改变世界的力量
The power to reshape the world.
拿去
Go on.
很安全
It's safe.
感觉一下你的未来
Touch your destiny.
我也带了礼物给你
I have brought something for you as well.
你的礼物
Your present.
都是死去的庞德的心意
Courtesy of the late Mr. Bond.
下令处死我的凶手
My executioner.
可惜没把你杀死
Overpraise, I'm afraid.
-我的手下会解决你的 -你的手下？
-But my people will finish the job. -Your people?
他们会让你在此自生自灭
Your people will leave you here to rot...
就像你对我一样
...just like you left me.
你还有我父亲
You and my father.
-你父亲… -他什么都不是
-Your father-- -My father was nothing.
他偷走我母亲的石油王国
His kingdom he stole from my mother.
我要夺回我的王国
The kingdom I will rightly take back.
你把她变成这样很得意吧
I hope you're proud of what you did to her.
这是你的功劳
I'm afraid it is you who deserve credit.
当时的她
When I took her...
真是天真无邪
...she was promise itself.
你却把她推入我这个火坑
You left her at the mercy of a man like me.
你毁了她
You ruined her.
为了什么？
For what?
只为了逮到我？
To get to me?
她比我好太多了
She's worth 50 of me.
这点我很同意
For once, I agree with you.
现在我们的命运相同
And now we also share a common fate.
你会跟
You will die...
这城市的人一起丧命
...along with everyone in this city...
西方国家的未来 也会毁于一旦
...and the bright, starry, oil-driven future of the West.
自从你派人刺杀我
Since you sent your man to kill me...
我就一直看着时钟 分分秒秒在走
...I've been watching time tick slowly away...
走向我的灭亡
...marching toward my own death.
现在你也一样
Now you can have the same pleasure.
我要你看着时钟
Watch these hands, M.
明天正午
By noon tomorrow...
就是你的死期
...your time is up.
我向你保证
And I guarantee you...
我绝不会错过
...I will not miss.
你好美
So beautiful.
好光滑
So smooth.
好温暖
So warm.
你怎么知道？
How would you know?
你为什么要这样？
Why are you like this?
因为庞德死了？
Because Bond is dead?
你不是要他死吗？
It's what you wanted.
当然了
Of course it's what I wanted.
他…
He was....
他是好情人吗？
He was a good lover?
你说呢？
What do you think?
难道我没感觉吗？
I wouldn't feel anything?
我一点都没有感觉
I feel nothing.
这样呢？
What about this?
你一定
But surely...
会感觉到这吧？
...you can feel this?
记得
Remember...
那些欢愉吗？
...pleasure?
里海
在这儿等
Wait here.
真是多事之秋
Always something.
先是赌场
First the casino.
现在是鱼子酱工厂
Now the caviar factory.
我是自由市场经济的奴隶
I am a slave to the free-market economy.
庞德还活着
Bond is alive.
这地方真是一团乱
Is nothing in this place straight?
你是谁？
Who are you?
你是怎么进来的？
And how did you get in?
我要通知警卫
I'll call security...
好好地谢谢他们
...and congratulate them.
来一杯吧？
Drink?
你不能像别人一样 打招呼吗？
Can't you say hello like a normal person?
快走
Get lost.
不是啦,走后门
No, no, no. Down the back.
你跟伊莉翠有什么来往？
What's your business with Elektra?
我以为你跟她才来电
I thought you were the one giving her the business.
她输给你一百万 好像理所当然
She drops $1 million in your casino, and you don't even blink.
她为什么付钱给你？
What's she paying you off for?
我劝你 跟这种男人在一起
You know, if I were you, a relationship with a man like that...
不会有好下场
...I wouldn't bet on it.
五千元的鱼子酱泡汤了
$5000 of beluga. Ruined.
跟核弹比起来 这算不了什么
That's nothing compared to what a nuclear bomb can do.
有一枚核弹遭窃
We had a nuclear bomb stolen this morning.
雷纳跟伊莉翠是一伙的
Renard and Elektra King are working together.
-我不知道 -你到底知道什么？！
-I didn't know. -Well, what do you know?!
Q先生会被气炸
Q's not gonna like this.
出去！
Get out!
救命啊！
Help!
现在
Now...
我们讲到哪儿？
...where were we?
-丢条绳子吧！ -不行,先说实话
-A rope, please! -No. The truth.
她把M夫人抓走
She has M.
-我不知情 -她想杀你灭口
-I know nothing. -Those blades were meant for you.
为什么？
What does Elektra King want you dead for?
是你毁了我的工厂
It was you who destroyed my factory.
是你把我的劳斯莱斯沉入湖底
Then you drown my Rolls-Royce...
你现在还想用鱼子酱把我淹死！
...and now you're trying to drown me in my own caviar!
救我上去！
Let me out!
可惜这儿没有香槟
Too bad we don't have any champagne.
或是酸奶
Or sour cream.
偶尔
Occasionally...
我会替她弄到俄制的器材
...I get equipment for her. Machinery. Russian stuff.
赌场的一百万呢？
And the payoff in the casino?
那是特别差事
It was a special job.
我侄子是海军
My nephew is in the navy.
他替她走私一些机器
He's smuggling some machinery for her.
-在哪儿？ -我不能说
-Where? -Absolutely not!
哪儿？！
Where?!
-哪儿？ -伊斯坦堡！
-Where? -Istanbul!
你！
You!
这金牙猴王 跑哪儿去了？
Where have you been, you gold-encrusted buffoon?
抱歉,我被撞昏了
Sorry, boss. I must have bumped my head.
把我救出来 我会让你知道什么是撞昏
Get me out of here, I'll show you what a bumped head feels like.
瞧
Look.
屋顶没了至少墙壁还在
We have no roof, but at least we have four good walls.
保险公司一定会抓狂
The insurance company is never going to believe this.
这里以前是KGB的分部
This used to be the KGB's Istanbul safe house. Now it's FSB.
现在是联邦安全局
Federal Security Bureau.
其实是换汤不换药
Same old friendly service with a new name.
-找到尼可莱吗？ -没有
-Did you raise Nikoli? -Nothing.
试着扫描紧急讯号
Try scanning the emergency frequencies.
可怜哪
Tragedy.
以前至少有一百个地方
In the old days, there were 1 00 places...
能让潜艇偷偷升到水面
...where a submarine could surface undetected.
潜艇？
Submarine?
你侄子的潜艇是什么型号？
What class is your nephew running?
你们称之为维特3型
Victor 3, you call it.
核能潜艇 他们要用潜艇的核子反应炉
Nuclear. He's not loading cargo. They want the sub to use the reactor.
没错
That's it.
把钸元素放进核子反应炉
Put weapons-grade plutonium in that sub's reactor...
就会造成严重的核爆
...instant, catastrophic meltdown.
看起来像是场意外
Making it all look just like an accident.
为什么？
But why?
里海的输油管
Because the existing pipelines from the Caspian Sea...
把石油运到北部
...go to the north. Here.
这里,再用油轮从黑海 运到伊斯坦堡
The oil is put on the tankers, shipped across the Black Sea to Istanbul.
核爆会摧毁伊斯坦堡
The explosion would destroy Istanbul...
污染整个博斯普鲁斯海峡几十年
...contaminating the Bosporus for decades.
这样一来 只有一个方法能输出石油
There'd be one way to get the oil out.
从南边到地中海
Down south to the Med.
金恩输油管
The King pipeline.
伊莉翠的输油管
Elektra's pipeline.
一定要找到尼克莱
We must find Nikoli.
尼克莱舰长？
Captain Nikoli?
你好
Sir.
准备装货了
Ready to load your cargo.
-我们只有几个小时 -你用最少的人员？
-We have only a few hours. -You came with skeleton crew?
-我们付不起太多人 -当然了
-That's all we can afford. -Of course.
给弟兄们的白兰地和点心
Some brandy and refreshments for your men.
谢谢你
Thank you.
早安
Good morning.
什么时候了？
What's the time?
你的死期到了
It's time for you to die.
我收到讯号
I've got something.
在紧急频道上
On the emergency frequency.
每十五秒发出两组六位数号码
Two six-digit numbers cycled every 1 5 seconds.
GPS定位讯号
A GPS signal. Position coordinates.
核弹晶片,M夫人
Locator card. M.
-这儿 -处女塔
-Here. -Maiden's Tower.
你去过吗？
Have you been there?
没有,蛮牛
No. Mr. Bullion.
有炸弹！
Bomb!
快走
Come on, come on.
你先请
After you.
我坚持
I insist.
最后的晚餐好吃吗？
Enjoyed your meal, boys?
把他们丢进海里喂鱼
Take them up and throw them in the sea.
反应炉在里面
The extruder's in here.
我得花半小时做成钸元素棒
It'll take half an hour to set up the machine to make the plutonium rod.
把他们带进来
Put them in here.
反应炉没问题
The reactor is secured.
一切都照计划进行
Everything is complete as planned.
-直升机来了吗？ -半小时后会来接我
-Is your helicopter ready? -It'll pick me up in half an hour.
这就是结局了
Then this is the end.
不,这是开始
This is the beginning.
世界将全面改观
The world will never be the same.
未来在你手中
The future is yours.
好好地玩吧
Have fun with it.
要是你不来搅局
If you'd kept away...
也许哪天我们真的能相爱
...we might've met in a few years and become lovers once more.
把她押去雷纳那儿
Take her to Renard.
她好漂亮
Pretty thing.
你也上过她？
You had her too?
我能让你称霸天下
I could've given you the world.
我绝不贪得无厌
The world is not enough.
你真傻
Foolish sentiment.
这是我家族的座右铭
Family motto.
考古学家在这里 挖出很多古董花瓶
They were digging near here, and they found some very pretty vases.
还找到这张椅子
They also found this chair.
现代人都不会念旧
I think we ignore the old ways at our peril...
对吧？
...don't you?
M夫人呢？
Where's M?
她就快粉身碎骨了
Soon she'll be everywhere.
你这么做
All this...
因为你爱上雷纳？
...because you fell for Renard?
再转五下你的脖子 就会被绞断
Five more turns and your neck will break.
我一向都很会玩弄男人
I've always had a power over men.
当我知道我父亲不付赎金
When I realized my father wouldn't rescue me from the kidnappers...
我就得跟绑匪结盟
...I knew I had to form another alliance.
你
You...
把雷纳玩弄于股掌
...turned Renard.
我也玩弄了你
Just like you...
只是你更容易玩弄
...only you were even easier.
我叫他真的动手伤我
I told him he had to hurt me.
看起来一定要像真的
He had to make it look real.
他不肯
When he refused...
我就说我自己来
...I told him I would do it myself.
你杀死了你父亲
So you killed your father.
是他先杀了我
He killed me.
他不肯付赎金就是杀了我
He killed me the day he refused to pay my ransom.
你全是为了石油吗？
Was this all about the oil?
那是我的石油
It is my oil.
我
Mine...
和我家族的石油
...and my family's.
流在我的血液里 比血还浓
It runs in my veins, thicker than blood.
我要重新整合天下
I'm going to redraw the map.
当我完成后 整个世界都会知道我
And when I'm through, the whole world will know my name...
和我外公的名字 我的族人的荣耀！
...my grandfather's name, the glory of my people!
没有人会相信核爆是场意外
No one will believe this meltdown was an accident.
他们一定会相信的
They will all believe.
你明白吗？
You understand?
没有人能抗拒我
Nobody can resist me.
你知道被绞死的感觉吗？
You know what happens when a man is strangled?
现在还不迟
It's not too late.
不必害死八百万人
Eight million people need not die.
你有机会时应该杀了我
You should've killed me when you had the chance.
但你下不了手 无法对我下手
But you couldn't. Not me.
无法对你心爱的女人下手
Not a woman you've loved.
我对你毫无感情
You meant nothing to me.
再
One...
转
...last...
最后一下
...screw.
老板
Boss...
你没死
...you're alive.
见到你真好
So glad to see you.
我也一样
Me too.
我在找一艘潜艇
I'm looking for a sub.
一艘大大黑黑的 舰长是我老朋友
It's big and black, and the driver is a good friend of mine.
带我去找他
Bring it to me.
可惜
What a shame.
他刚走不久
He's just gone.
他真的痛恨你
Zukovsky really hated you.
没问题了 你好了吗？
Everything's under control up here. Are you ready?
好了,该说晚安了
Time to say good night.
你不会冷血地
You can't kill me.
杀我
Not in cold blood.
阻止他
Call him off.
我不想再说一次
I won't ask again.
阻止他
Call him off.
快阻止他！
Call him off!
你下不了手
You wouldn't kill me.
你没这么狠心
You'd miss me.
快下潜！
Dive! Bond--
我绝不心软
I never miss.
她人呢？
Where is she?
以为我忘了？
Thought I'd forgotten?
下潜一百英尺后直航
Level at 1 00 feet.
稳住了
Hold her steady.
一百英尺
Level at 1 00 feet.
只要逼他们浮出水面
If we can force them up to the surface...
潜艇会被间谍卫星发现
...they'll show up on the spy satellite...
海军就会赶来
...bring out the navy.
快,起来！
Come on. Get up!
快走！
Over there. Move!
给我过去！
Move! Go, go!
过去！
Get over there!
别乱动！
Stay!
手举起来！
Up!
拉平！拉平了！
Get us level! Level!
全被打烂了！
It's all smashed!
克莉莫丝？
Christmas?
我们应该笔直上升？
So we're going up then?
我稍微算错了
Slight miscalculation.
抓紧了！
Hold on!
千万要抓紧
Hold on, hold on.
小心了
Brace yourself.
进水了！
It's flooding!
快爬到上面去
Get up to the hatch.
快点！快！
Damn! Come on!
快！
Go, go!
他启动反应炉！
He's opened up the reactor!
把自己锁在里面
And locked himself in!
我得去找他
I have to get up there to him.
我们只有一次机会
We have one chance.
我要游到外面 再从逃生舱口进入反应炉室
I'll get out and back in through the reactor room escape hatch.
红灯一亮 就按下去让我进去
When the light goes red, press this button so I can get back in.
这太危险了
James, it's too risky.
要是我失败
If I don't make it...
你就从这里逃生 关上舱门
...use this chamber to get out. Close the hatch.
一路要吐气 关起来
Exhale all the way up. Close it.
救命啊！
Help!
快点！
Come on, come on!
只要反应炉不爆炸
We're safe from the radiation...
我们就没有辐射线的危险
...if the reactor coolant doesn't burst.
要是他把钸元素插进去
If he had gotten the plutonium rod in the reactor...
伊斯坦堡就完了
...we could've written off the whole city.
欢迎加入我的核子家族
Welcome to my nuclear family.
你真的愿意为她死吗？
Are you really gonna commit suicide for her?
你忘了,我早就死了
You forget, I'm already dead.
你没听说吗？
Haven't you heard?
她也死了
So is she.
你在说谎
You're lying.
骗子！
Liar!
她在地狱等你
She's waiting for you.
氢气指数过高
The hydrogen gas level's too high.
只要稍微有一点火花 反应炉就会爆炸
One spark and the reactor'll blow.
我得想办法阻止
I have to stop it.
到上面的鱼雷发射孔等我
Go to the top of the sub. Meet me in the torpedo bay.
反应炉进水了
The reactor is flooded.
就算爆炸也不会有危险
So it's safe even if this place blows.
不,这样不行
No, it's simply not the case.
在那之前
Before that.
有消息吗？
Any word?
还没有
Still no contact.
我一直想在土耳其过圣诞
Always wanted to have Christmas in Turkey.
你在笑我吗？
Was that a Christmas joke?
我笑你？不会的
From me? No.
绝对不会
Never.
该是你拆礼物的时候了吧？
So isn't it time you unwrapped your present?
是啊
Oh, I think so.
瞧,那是什么？
Look. What's that?
-定位晶片 -他一定在附近
-The card. -He must be nearby.
哪儿？
Where?
-在哪儿？ -这侦测到了
-Where? -It picks up...
体温,人体是橘色的
...body heat, so humans come out orange.
那儿
There.
我以为你说他跟 琼斯博士在一起？
I thought you said he was with Dr. Jones?
越来越红了
It's getting redder.
一定是千禧虫在作祟
Must be a premature form of the millennium bug.
我搞错了
I was wrong about you.
什么意思？
How so?
我以为圣诞节一年只有一次
007情报员会回来